cardiffmet.ac.uk 2019-06-22

# Cardiff Metropolitan University - Cookies and Privacy Statement

Cardiff Metropolitan University takes responsibility for protecting your privacy when you use our websites and services. This statement describes why we collect information from you and how this information will be processed.   

**Please note:** Non-Cardiff Metropolitan University websites are not covered by this statement. However where relevant we have provided links to further information. 

Cardiff Metropolitan University is the Data Controller and is committed to protecting the rights of individuals in line with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). 

### 1\. Information Collection 

Anonymous information is collected automatically through the use of Cookies, and Personally Identifiable Information (PII) is collected from web-based forms which you yourself have completed.

### 2\. Use of Cookies 

Cookies are files, sent by us to your computer or other access device, which can then be accessed when you visit our websites in the future, allowing us to record your browsing activity. These Cookies are used by: 

**a) Google Analytics  **

Google Analytics is a statistical tool that analyses the usage of websites by collecting internet log and behavioral information in an anonymous form. This information is then used to report on activity and provide an indication of website usage, which enables us to provide a better service on-site and inform our advertising off-site. (See also 4. Advertising – Google Ads) 

Please follow this link for more information on [Google Analytics and your privacy](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245). 

**b) Authentication  **

In addition, Cookies are used to aid service and system access by allowing you to move around within our websites without having to re-authenticate. Such Cookies are automatically removed from your computer when you close down your browser windows. 

**Disabling Cookies**. You can choose to disable the use of cookies by clicking on the **‘Disable Cookies’** button. Some cookies are necessary to enable core functionality of the website. These can only be disabled by changing your browser preferences but this may impact your experience across our sites. For further information about Cookies and instructions on their control and deletion please visit <http://www.aboutcookies.org/>.  

### 3\. Personal Information 

PII (such as your name, address, telephone number and email address) that you directly provide to us through the use of web-based forms will be stored securely; only be accessed by authorized Cardiff Metropolitan University personnel and will only be used for its intended purpose. The University is lawful in processing this data because you have given consent (under Article 6 of the GDPR). 

**Third Parties and PII**

The University works with the following third parties in terms of PII: 

**a) Campus Management**

Cardiff Metropolitan University uses PII collected and stored by Campus Management Corp UK on behalf of the University through the use of specific URLs relating to online forms for prospectus requests, open day and applicant day registrations. 

For further information on how your data is stored by Campus Management, please read the ‘Admissions Privacy Policy’ at: <https://www.campusmanagement.com/about-us/privacy/>. 

**b) Qualtircs**

Cardiff Metropolitan University uses PII collected and stored by Qualtrics on behalf of the University through the use of specific URLs relating to online forms for enquiries, event bookings and applications. 

For further information on how your data is stored by Qualtrics, please visit: <https://www.qualtrics.com/privacy-statement/> and pay attention to section 3: 'Data Collected by Customers'.

**c) Uni Quest**

Cardiff Metropolitan University uses PII collected and stored by Uni Quest on behalf of the International Office at the University, through the use of specific URLs relating to online forms for International Student enquiries and applications.

For further information on how your data is collected and shared between the University and Uni Quest, please visit: <http://www.uni-quest.co.uk/privacy-policy/>[ ](http://www.uni-quest.co.uk/privacy-policy/)

**d) Live Chat Inc.**

Cardiff Metropolitan University uses PII collected and stored by Live Chat Inc. on behalf of the University through the use of specific software for Live Online Chat to support Clearing applications and enquiries via the University website.

For further information on how your data is stored by Live Chat Inc, please visit: <https://www.livechatinc.com/privacy-policy/>.

Unless required or permitted do so by law, we will not otherwise share, sell or distribute any of the information you provide us without your consent.  

### 4\. Advertising 

The University website currently collects and uses non-PII data from your browsing activity, for marketing/remarketing purposes across the channels below. By accepting the terms of this Cookie and Privacy Statement, you are providing consent for us to serve you with such advertising. 

**a) Facebook and Instagram  **

The University website uses the 'Facebook Pixel' (a small block of code) in order to track which pages of the website you visit and what actions you may take. This allows us to serve you with targeted and relevant advertising across the Facebook and Instagram platforms ("Custom Audiences from your Website") and send information about any actions you may take ("Event Data") to Facebook to track conversions ("Conversion Tracking"). 

Find out more about the [Facebook Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy).

You can also [manage your Facebook Ad preferences](https://www.facebook.com/about/basics/advertising/ad-preferences) via your personal Facebook account.  

**b) Twitter  **

The University website uses the Twitter 'Universal Website Tag' (a small block of code) to track which pages of the website you visit, in order for us to utilise the 'Custom Audiences' and 'Conversion Tracking' features of Twitter Ads. We then use this information to serve you with relevant and targeted adverts across the Twitter platform. 

Find out more about the [Twitter Privacy Policy](https://twitter.com/en/privacy).  

**c) Google Ads (Search, Display and YouTube)  **

The University uses the Google AdWords platform to serve relevant and targeted advertising to visitors of the University website. Data (browsing data) collected via Google Analytics is used to create custom audience profiles. These profiles are used to re-market and serve you with relevant adverts across the Google search and display networks including YouTube. Any user actions from such advertising (e.g. clicks or event registrations) is passed back to Google Analytics to allow the University to track conversions and measure the impact of any such advertising. 

Find out more about the [Google Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en-GB&gl=uk). 

You can also [control how adverts are served](https://adssettings.google.com/) to you across the Google network. 

### 5\. Your Rights

If the University processes personal information about you, you have the right to invoke the following individual rights. You have the right to: 

\- access your personal information 

\- object to the processing of your personal information, 

\- rectify any inaccurately held data

\- restrict the processing of certain personal information 

\- data portability 

\- object to the processing of your personal data 

Please visit the Information Commissioner Office's (ICO) website for further information in relation to your rights. <https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/>[ ](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/)

If you have previously provided consent for the processing of your personal data, you also have the right to withdraw this consent at any time, without affecting the lawfulness of the processing based on consent before its withdrawal.  

If you wish to make a complaint about the way your personal data has been processed you can submit your concerns in writing to:

Information & Data Compliance Officer  
Secretariat Unit  
Cardiff Metropolitan University  
Llandaff Campus  
Western Avenue Cardiff  
CF5 2YB   

If this process does not resolve your issue, or if you wish to take your complaint further, you have the right to contact the Information Commissioner. The contact details are:  

Information Commissioner’s Office   
Wycliffe House   
Water Lane   
Wilmslow   
Cheshire   
SK9 5AF   

 ** _Last  Updated: Aug 2 2018_**

###
